# Alexander Wiegman

Silicon & Central Valley, California, USA | hello@madicetea.me | (209)-410-8047 | https://github.com/madicetea

## **Summary**

Alex is an experienced cyber security analyst with a passion for systems, architectures, networks, and their security. He seeks a challenging position, to find and apply modern solutions for malicious cyber campaigns targeting companies, infrastructure, and governments large and small, and for opportunities to enact methods to disrupt them.

## **Work Experience**

Cyber Security Analyst PerimeterX, Inc. (San Mateo, USA) 11/2019 – (current)

Worldwide leader in behavioural bot management protection for e-Commerce apps. | https://www.perimeterx.com

- Lead and mentor to customers and multiple internal departments, alike. Evolved an onboarding program for the WFH era.
- Specialties in technical integrations, data logging solutions, high-value item AIO software research, JavaScript supply-chain risk, and information processing and asset (cookie, scripts, etc.) identification questionnaires.
- Automated alerting patterns and data query through parameterisation and scripting in YAML, SQL, JS, and Python.
- Identified multiple specific key patterns in anomalous network & client-side data points from Petabyte-scale data, then synthesised these into backend detection models to prevent and terminate account takeover, fraud, and card theft.

#### **Cyber Security Analyst (Intern)**

Pipeline Security, K.K. (Tokyo, Japan)

02/2019 - 07/2019

Leading provider of DNS security intelligence feeds to the Asia-Pacific (APAC) region. | https://pipelinesecurity.net

- Researched internal risk vulnerability by configuring secure policies & installing updates for cloud-hosted virtual machines, and programming a BIND DNS server with Response-Policy Zones to examine SIEM data visualization by ELK.
- Transformed customer image by contributing four articles of how-to documentation and negotiating a redesign of knowledgebase and homepage with co-workers, while providing production support to three customer companies.
- Investigated a false-positive spam listing, due to an issue identified in a shared hosting provider's nameservers (NS).
- Slashed company expenditure by facilitating secure data destruction / modernizing OS & software on the computers.

Website Developer, Security Engineer

Junction Ltd. (Tokyo, Japan)

11/2016 - 05/2017

Largest international hackathon in Japan, supported by many partnering sponsors. | https://www.hackjunction.com

- Relaxed worries of 550 participants towards *Junction Tokyo*'s website by responsibly reporting configuration flaws in a form, integrating an HTTPS certificate, and improving loading & development time with a WordPress redesign.

## **Skills**

Certifications / Licenses AWS Cloud Practitioner (-2024); Microsoft Azure SysAdmin [Associate] (-2022);

CompTIA Security+ / A+ (-2024), Mobility+ / CDIA+ (lifetime)

Operating Systems Windows, Mac OSX, Linux (Fedora, ChromeOS, Debian, CentOS, Android, Ubuntu)

Programming, Scripting UNIX bash, SQL, VCL, JavaScript, Python, HTML, YAML, JSON, Java, Ruby

Programs / Toolkits AWS EC2, CloudFormation, Fastly, Google APIs, BigQuery, Redash, Prometheus, ELK,

CircleCI, git, SSH, curl, Insomnia, DNS/BIND, Android Studio, Trello, Confluence, JIRA

Websites Created / http://www.pxcops.company [2020-], https://madicetea.me [2018-]

Contributed <a href="https://peakstudentcouncil.org">https://peakstudentcouncil.org</a> [-2019], <a href="https://tokyo.hackjunction.com">https://peakstudentcouncil.org</a> [-2019]

Accomplishments CircleCl Orbtoberfest Winner (2020), GitHub Hacktoberfest Winner (2018 - 2020),

ICMCP Black Hat Scholar (2017)

### **Education**

The University of Tokyo [UTokyo]

Bachelor's Degree in Environmental Science

(Tokyo, Japan)

09/2015 - 09/2019

Minors in Informatics & Science and Technology Studies